Preliminary Inventory to the Rand Corporation Reports, 1965-1972
Hoover Institution Archives
Rand Corporation Reports,
1965-1972
76017
Rand Corporation
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Relates to the organization, operations, motivation, and morale of Viet Cong and North Vietnamese troops, 1964-1968, based on 2400 interviews with Vietnamese
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1976.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Viet Cong; Guerrillas--Vietnam; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975; Vietnam
Container List
- User's Guide to the Rand Interviews in Vietnam, W. Phillips Davison, March 1972, R-1024 (Box 1)
- Viet Cong Motivation and Morale in 1964: A Preliminary Report, J. C. Donnell, G. J. Pauker, J. J. Zasloff, March 1965., RM-4507/3
- Some Impressions of the Effects of Military Operations on Viet Cong Behavior, L. Goure, August 1965., RM-4517-1
- Evolution of a Vietnamese Village -- Part I: The Present, After Eight Months of Pacification, R. M. Pearce, April 1965., RM-4552-1; (2 copies)
- Evolution of a Vietnamese Village -- Part II: The Past, August 1945 to April 1964, R. M. Pearce, April 1966., RM-4692-1
- Some Impressions of Viet Cong Vulnerabilities: An Interim Report, L. Goure, C.A.H. Thomson, August 1965., RM-4699-1
- Political Motivation of the Viet Cong: The Vietminh Regroupees, J. J. Zasloff, May 1968., RM-4703/2
- Viet Cong Motivation and Morale: The Special Case of Chieu Hoi, J. M. Carrier, C.A.H. Thomson, May 1966., RM-4830-2
- Observations on the Chieu Hoi Program, L. W. Pye, January 1966., RM-4864-1
- Some Findings of the Viet Cong Motivation and Morale Study: June-December 1965, L. Goure, A. J. Russo, D. Scott, February 1966., RM-4911-2
- Some Effects of Military Operations on Viet Cong Attitudes, F. H. Denton, November 1966., RM-4966-1
- A Profile of Viet Cong Cadres, W. P. Davison, J. J. Zasloff, June 1966., RM-4983-1
- A Profile of the PAVN Soldier in South Vietnam, K. Kellen, June 1966., RM-5013-1
- Evolution of a Vietnamese Village -- Part III: Duc Lap Since November 1964 and Some Comments on Village Pacification, R. M. Pearce, February 1967., RM-5086-1
- A Look at the VC Cadres: Dinh Tuong Province, 1965-1966, D.W.P. Elliott, C.A.H. Thomson, March 1967., RM-5114-1
- Origins of the Insurgency in South Vietnam, 1954-1960: The Role of the Southern Vietminh Cadres, J. J. Zasloff, May 1968., RM-5163/2
- Insurgent Organization and Operations: A Case Study of the Viet Cong in the Delta, 1964-1966, M. Anderson, M. Arnsten, H. Averch, August 1967., RM-5239-1; (2 copies) (Box 2)
- Some Observations on Viet Cong Operations in the Villages, W. P. Davison, May 1968., RM-5267/2
- Two Analytical Aids for Use with the Rand Interviews, F. Denton, May 1967., RM-5338
- The War in the Delta: Views from Three Viet Cong Battalions, M. Gurtov, September 1967., RM-5353-1
- Viet Cong Cadres and the Cadre System: A Study of the Main and Local Forces, M. Gurtov, December 1967., RM-5414-1
- Viet Cong Logistics, L. P. Holliday, R. M. Gurfield, June 1968., RM-5423-1
- An Evaluation of Chemical Crop Destruction in Vietnam, R. Betts, F. Denton, October 1967., RM-5446-1
- A Statistical Analysis of the U.S. Crop Seraying Program in South Vietnam, A. J. Russo, October 1967., RM-5450-1
- A View of the VC: Elements of Cohesion in the Enemy Camp in 1966-1967, K. Kellen, November 1969., RM-5462-1
- Viet Cong Recruitment: Why and How Men Join, J. C. Donnell, December 1967., RM-5486-1
- The Viet Cong Style of Politics, N. Leites, May 1969., RM-5487-1 (Box 3)
- Inducements and Deterrents to Defection: An Analysis of the Motives of 125 Defectors, L. Goure, August 1968., RM-5522-1
- The Insurgent Environment, R. M. Pearce, May 1969., RM-5533-1
- Volunteers for the Viet Cong, F. Denton, September 1968., RM-5647
- Pacification and the Viet Cong System in Dinh Tuong: 1966-1967, D.W.P. Elliott, W. A. Stewart, January 1969., RM-5788
- The Viet Cong in Saigon: Tactics and Objectives During the Tet Offensive, V. Pohle, January 1969., RM-5799
- Documents of an Elite Viet Cong Delta Unit: The Demolition Platoon of the 514th Battalion -- Part One: Unit Composition and Personnel, D.W.P. Elliott, M. Elliott, May 1969., RM-5848
- Documents of an Elite Viet Cong Delta Unit: The Demolition Platoon of the 514th Battalion -- Part Two: Party Organization, D.W.P. Elliott, M. Elliott, May 1969., RM-5849
- Documents of an Elite Viet Cong Delta Unit: The Demolition Platoon of the 514th Battalion -- Part Three: Military Organization and Activities, D.W.P. Elliott, M. Elliott, May 1969., RM-5850
- Documents of an Elite Viet Cong Delta Unit: The Demolition Platoon of the 514th Battalion -- Part Four: Political Indoctrination and Military Training, D.W.P. Elliott, M. Elliott, May 1969., RM-5851
- Documents of an Elite Viet Cong Delta Unit: The Demolition Platoon of the 514th Battalion -- Part Five: Personal Letters, D.W.P. Elliott, M. Elliott, May 1969., RM-5852
- Conversations with Enemy Soldiers in Late 1968 /Early 1969: A Study of Motivation and Morale, K. Kellen, September 1970., RM-6131-1
- Rallying Potential Among the North Vietnamese Armed Forces, A. Sweetland, December 1970., RM-6375-1